Register of the Alexander Vardy Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- RADIO LIBERTY BROADCAST TRANSCRIPTS, 1963-1989
  - About
    - Genetics
      - "Sovremennaia mysl',", 1971 (Box-folder 36: 1)
      - "Vnutrennii mir cheloveka," #16-33, 1976 (Folder 36: 2)
      - "Zavtrashnii den' planety,", 1974-1977 (Folder 36: 3)
      - "Zigmund Freid i ego kritiki," #1-6, 1977 (Folder 36: 4)
    - Ginzburg, E.
      - "From the Other Shore," #1192-1230, 1980 (Folder 36: 5-7)
      - Radio composition on Ginzburg's book Krutoi marshrut, 1967 (Box-folder 37: 1-3)
    - Gorky, Maksim. (Folder 37: 4)
      Includes special broadcast transcript "K 100-letiiu so dnia rozhdeniia Maksima Gor'kogo," 1968
    - Grossman, Vasilii
      - General (Folder 37: 5)
      - Broadcast transcript "S drugogo berega: K 75-letiiu pisatelia i vykhodu ego romana Zhizn' i Sud'ba,", 1980-1983 (Folder 37: 6)
      - Broadcast transcript "S drugogo berega: K 75-letiiu pisatelia i vykhodu ego romana Zhizn' i Sud'ba,", 1980-1983 (Box-folder 38: 1)
    - Heidegger, Martin, 1969 (Folder 38: 2)
    - Historical materialism
      - General (Folder 38: 3)
      - Broadcast transcripts (Folder 38: 4-5)
    - Holocaust, Jewish (1939-1946)
      - General (Folder 38: 6)
      - Broadcast transcripts
        - "Discussiia vyzvannaia pokazom telefil'ma 'Golocost' vo Frantsii,", 1979 (Folder 38: 7)
        - "Fil'm 'Istrebleniie' i debaty o sroke davnosti,", 1979 (Folder 38: 6)
    - Human rights, 1976-1980 (Folder 39: 1-2)
      See also Torture
    - IAkir, Petr, "Memuary," #1-5, 1971-1972 (Folder 39: 3-4)
    - Ideology of hatred
      - General, 1963-1976 (Folder 39: 5)
      - Broadcast transcripts (Folder 39: 6)
      - Broadcast transcripts (Box-folder 40: 1-3)
    - Jaspers, Karl, 1969 (Folder 40: 4)
    - Kafka, Franz (Folder 40: 5)
    - Kandel, Feliks, "Zona otdykha,", 1979 November (Folder 40: 6)
    - Keins, John (Folder 40: 7)
    - Khazanov, Boris, "Glukhoi nevedomoi taigoiu,", 1976 (Folder 40: 8)
    - Khenkin, Kiril, "Okhotnik vverkh nogami," #2-16, 1980 (Folder 40: 9)
    - Khenkin, Kiril, "Okhotnik vverkh nogami," #2-16, 1980 (Box-folder 41: 1-2)
    - Khrushchev, Nikita, 1971 (Folder 41: 3)
    - Kochetov, Vsevolod, "Smuta novogo vremeni: Ili Udivitel'nye Pokhozhdeniia Vani Chemodanova,", 1970 (Folder 41: 4)
    - Koestler, Arthur, 1971-1972 (Folder 41: 5-6)
    - Kolman, Arnosht, 1978 (Folder 41: 7)
    - Kolman, Ernst, "Vozmozhen li sotsializm marksistskoi modeli?", 1979 (Folder 41: 8)
    - Kopelev, Lev, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 42: 1)
    - Krigel, Frantishek, 1976-1978 (Folder 42: 2)
    - Labor camps
      - General (Folder 42: 3-8)
      - General (Box-folder 43: 1-2)
      - Broadcast transcripts (Folder 43: 3-6)
      - Broadcast transcripts (Box-folder 44: 1-4)
      - Miscellaneous (Folder 44: 5)
    - Lenin, V. I., 1970-1980 (Folder 44: 6-7)
    - Mandelshtam, Nadezhda, 1982 December (Box-folder 45: 1)
    - Mao Tse-tung, 1975 (Folder 45: 2)
    - Marcuse, Herbert, 1968 (Folder 45: 3)
    - Marx, Karl
      - General. (Folder 45: 4-6)
      - "Stoletiie so dnia smerti Karla Marksa," #1-9, 1983 (Folder 45: 7)
      - "Stoletiie so dnia smerti Karla Marksa," #1-9, 1983 (Box-folder 46: 1)
    - Marxism, "Marksizm ustami Lenina," #1-16, 1970 (Folder 46: 2-3)
    - Medvedev, Roy, 1979 (Folder 46: 4)
    - Michunovich, Velko, "Moskovskie gody 1956-1958," #1-6, 1977-1978 (Folder 46: 5)
    - Nekrich, Aleksandr, "Otreshis' ot strakha," #1-31, 1979 (Folder 46: 6-7)
    - Nekrich, Aleksandr, "Otreshis' ot strakha," #1-31, 1979 (Folder 47: 1-3)
    - Neo-Slavophiles
      - General (Folder 47: 4)
      - Broadcast transcripts (Folder 47: 5)
    - 'Old Bolsheviks' (Box 48)
      - General (Folder 48: 1)
      - Broadcast transcripts
        - General (Folder 48: 2-3)
        - "Soperniki i zhertvy," #1-12, 1968 (Folder 48: 4)
    - Orwell, George, 1960-1975 (Folder 48: 5)
    - Pasternak, Boris, 1960-1975 (Folder 48: 6)
    - Philosophy
      - General (Folder 48: 7)
      - General (Box-folder 49: 1-3)
      - "Drevniie filosofii mira," #2-21, 1974 (Folder 49: 4)
      - "Filosofiia novogo vremeni," #19-24, 1977 (Folder 49: 5)
      - "Filosofiia v meniaiushchemsia mire," #1-42, 1977 (Folder 49: 6-7)
      - "Filosofiia v meniaiushchemsia mire," #1-42, 1977 (Box-folder 50: 1-2)
      - "Filosofiia v Rossii: Idei i problemy," #1-23, 1978 (Folder 50: 3-4)
      - "Filosofiia srednevekov'ia," #1-13, 1976 (Folder 50: 5)
      - "Gumanitarnye nauiki v sovremennoi Anglii,", 1975 (Folder 50: 6)
      - "Idei sovremennogo mira," #2-4, 1978-1979 (Folder 50: 7)
      - "Mify 20-go veka," #1-14, 1970 (Folder 50: 8)
      - "Novye tendentsii sovremennoi filosofii," #1-18, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 51: 1-2)
      - "Rol' filosofii v sovremennom mire," #1-10, 1975-1976 (Folder 51: 3)
    - Pliushch, Leonid, "Eticheskaia ustanovka,", 1970 (Folder 51: 4)
    - Podrabinek, A., "Karatel'naia meditsina," #1-26, 1977 (Folder 51: 5-7)
    - Podrabinek, A., "Karatel'naia meditsina," #1-26, 1977 (Box-folder 52: 1-2)
    - Propaganda and ideology, 1973-1977 (Folder 52: 3-5)
    - Psychiatry, 1958-1982 (Folder 52: 6-7)
      Includes Samizdat material
    - Psychiatry, 1958-1982 (Box-folder 53: 1-7)
    - Psychiatry, 1958-1982 (Box-folder 54: 1-2)
    - Repressed nations, 1987-1989 (Folder 54: 3)
    - Sakharov, Andrei.
      See also WRITINGS BY OTHERS
      - General (Folder 54: 4-5)
      - General (Box-folder 55: 1)
      - Broadcasts transcripts (Folder 55: 2-3)
    - Science
      - General (Folder 55: 4-5)
      - General (Box 56-57)
      - General (Box-folder 58: 1)
      - Broadcast transcripts (Folder 58: 2-6)
      - Broadcast transcripts (Box-folder 59: 1-5)
    - Serebriakova, Galina
      - General (Folder 59: 6)
      - "Smerch," #1-4, 1968 (Folder 59: 7)
    - Shafarevitch, Igor (Box 60)
      - General (Folder 60: 1)
      - Broadcast transcripts (Folder 60: 2)
    - Shalamov, Varlaam
      - General (Folder 60: 3)
      - Broadcasts
        - General (Folder 60: 4)
        - "Kolymskie rasskazy,", 1967-1983 (Folder 60: 5-7)
        - "Kolymskie rasskazy,", 1967-1983 (Box-folder 61: 1-5)
    - Sholokhov, Mikhail, 1964 September (Box-folder 62: 1)
    - Solzhenitsyn, Aleksandr.
      - General (Folder 62: 2-6)
      - General (Box-folder 63: 1-5)
      - Broadcast transcripts (Folder 63: 6)
      - Broadcast transcripts (Box 64-65)
    - Soviet Union (Box 66)
      - Armed Forces, "Istoriia Sovetskoi Armii,"., 1964-1974 (Folder 66: 1-4)
        Mostly history of the Second World War. Includes clippings
      - History
        - General. "Ot Cheka do KGB: Istoriia organov gosbezopasnosti v Sovetskom Soiuze," #1-172, 1968-1972 (Folder 66: 5-6)
        - General. "Ot Cheka do KGB: Istoriia organov gosbezopasnosti v Sovetskom Soiuze," #1-172, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 67: 1-6)
        - General. "Ot Cheka do KGB: Istoriia organov gosbezopasnosti v Sovetskom Soiuze," #1-172, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 68: 1-3)
        - Revolution
          - "Stranitsy iz revoliutsionnogo proshlogo," #53-179, 1967-1969 (Folder 68: 4-5)
          - "Sovremennoe obshchestvo: istoricheskoe znachenie Oktiabr'skoi revoliutsii,", 1968 (Folder 68: 6)
      - Intellectual life (Box 69)
        - "Russkaia svobodnaia mysl'," #1-110, 1959-1963 (Folder 69: 1-3)
        - "Sorevnovanie Mirovozzrencheskikh idei,", 1966-1967 (Folder 69: 4)
      - Politics and government -, 1945-1991
        - "Pokazatel'nye protsessy 1937-1938 godov,", n.d. (Folder 69: 5)
        - "Analiz tekushchikh sobytii v Sovetskom Soiuze,", 1967-1971 (Folder 69: 6)
        - "Politicheskie protsessy v posleoktiabr'skoi Rossii," #1-31, 1971 (Folder 69: 7-8)
        - "Politicheskie protsessy v posleoktiabr'skoi Rossii," #1-31, 1971 (Box-folder 70: 1)
      - Social conditions -, 1970-1991
        - "Inkvizitsiia 20-go veka," #1-16, 1970 (Folder 70: 2-3)
        - "Pis'ma i dokumenty: Dnevnik mesiachnoi golodovki v Permskom politicheskom lagere,", 1970-1974 (Folder 70: 4)
    - Stalin, Joseph
      - General (Folder 70: 5)
      - "History of the Personality Cult," #1-57, 1969-1970 (Folder 70: 6-7)
      - "History of the Personality Cult," #1-57, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 71: 1-2)
      - "K 30-letiiu so dnia smerti Stalina," #1-44, 1983 (Folder 71: 3-7)
      - "K 30-letiiu so dnia smerti Stalina," #1-44, 1983 (Box-folder 72: 1)
    - Steiner, Karl, "7000 dnei v Sibiri," #1-4, 1971 (Folder 72: 2)
    - Terror.
      Includes psychological terror
      - General (Folder 72: 3-7)
      - Broadcast transcripts (Box-folder 73: 1-4)
    - Torture and human rights, 1977-1981 (Folder 73: 5-6)
    - Trotsky, Leon (Box 74)
      - General (Folder 74: 1-3)
      - Broadcast transcripts
        - General (Folder 74: 4-6)
        - General (Folder 75: 1-2)
        - Special programs (Folder 75: 3)
    - Ulanovskaia, M., "Konets sroka," #1-10, 1977 (Folder 75: 4-5)
    - Voinovitch, Vladimir, "Pretendent na prestol ili novye prikliucgeniia soldata Ivana Chonkina," #1-27, 1980 (Folder 75: 6)
    - Voinovitch, Vladimir, "Pretendent na prestol ili novye prikliucgeniia soldata Ivana Chonkina," #1-27, 1980 (Box-folder 76: 1-2)
    - World War, 1939-1945 - Soviet Union
      - General (Folder 76: 3)
      - Broadcast transcripts, "K 30-letiiu Pobedy,", 1975 (Folder 76: 4-5)
    - Youth, 1977-1978 (Folder 76: 6-7)
  - By or with the participation of (Box 77)
    - Adler, Fridrikh, "Rossiia vchera, segodnia, zavtra,", 1968 (Folder 77: 1)
    - Allilueva, Svetlana, interview, 1967 October (Folder 77: 2)
    - Belinkov, Arkadii, 1969-1981 (Folder 77: 3-5)
    - Conquest, Robert, "Bol'shoi Terror," #1-12, 1969 (Folder 77: 6-7)
      Includes interview
    - Dintses, Aleksandr, "Sovremennyi sovetskii ispravitel'no-trudovoi lager'," interview, 1967 (Folder 77: 8)
    - Ivanov, Valentin, 1978 (Folder 77: 9)
    - Krotkov, IUrii (Box 78)
      - General, 1967-1976 (Folder 78: 1-2)
      - "Ia iz Moskvy," #1-6, 1967 (Folder 78: 3)
    - Kuznetsov, A.
      - General (Folder 78: 4-6)
      - "Besedy Anatoliia Kuznetsova," #1-242, 1972-1978 (Box-folder 79: 1-6)
    - Marchenko, Anatolii, "Ot Tarusy do Chuny," #1-7, 1976 (Box-folder 80: 1)
    - Smolkin, Petr, "Smolkinskie besedy," #1-318, 1956-1967 (Folder 80: 2-7)
    - Smolkin, Petr, "Smolkinskie besedy," #1-318, 1956-1967 (Box-folder 81: 1-8)
    - Smolkin, Petr, "Smolkinskie besedy," #1-318, 1956-1967 (Box-folder 82: 1-5)
    - Svirskii, Grigorii
      - General (Folder 82: 6-7)
      - "Literatura nravstvennogo soprotivleniia," #1-65, 1976-1978 (Folder 82: 8)
      - "Literatura nravstvennogo soprotivleniia," #1-65, 1976-1978 (Folder 83: 1-6)
      - "Literatura nravstvennogo soprotivleniia," #1-65, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 84: 1)
      - Special programs (Folder 84: 2)
    - Topol, Eduard, "Zhurnalist dlia Brezhneva," #1-12, 1982 (Folder 84: 3-5)
    - Turchin, Valentin, "Inertsiia strakha," #1-29, 1977-1978 (Folder 84: 6)
    - Turchin, Valentin, "Inertsiia strakha," #1-29, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 85: 1-5)
    - Vardy, A.
      - "Frantisheku Krigeliu-70 Let,", n.d. (Folder 85: 6)
      - "K Mezhdunarodnomu zhenskomu dniu,", n.d. (Folder 85: 7)
      - "O 15-om Mezhdunarodnom Filosofskom Kongresse,", n.d. (Folder 85: 8)
      - "O teleperedachakh Valentina Zorina,", n.d. (Folder 85: 9)
      - "Ob epigonakh gitlerovskikh natsistov,", n.d. (Folder 85: 10)
      - "Pravda o lageriakh,", n.d. (Folder 85: 11)
      - "Problemy obshchestvovedeniia,", n.d.
        - "O tezise: 'Bytie opredeliaet soznanie,' O Politicheskikh posledstviiakh etoi filosofskoi formuly," #4 (Folder 85: 12)
        - "O prichinakh protivopostavleniia v sovetskom obshchestvovedenii materii i soznaniia," #5 (Folder 85: 13)
        - "Verno li sovetskoe osveshchenie otnosheniia materii i soznaniia?" #6 (Folder 85: 14)
        - "Material'no li soznanie?" #7 (Box-folder 86: 1)
        - "Dlia chego provozglashen v sovetskom obshchestvovedenii 'Osnovnoi vopros filisofii'?" #8 (Folder 86: 2)
        - "Pochemu v sovetskom obshchestvovedenii mnogo vzaimoiskliuchaiushchikh utverzhdenii i teorii/?" #9 (Folder 86: 3)
        - "O politicheskikh posledstviiakh resheniia sovetskimi teoretikami osnovnogo voprosa sovetskoi filosofii," #10 (Folder 86: 4)
      - "Radiozhurnal: Po Sovetskomu Soiuzu,", n.d. (Folder 86: 5)
      - "Vosstanie v Novocherkasske,", n.d. (Folder 86: 6)
      - "Chast' pravdy o kollektivizatsii,", 1963 (Folder 86: 7)
      - "Khrushchev o Staline i stalinizme,", 1963 (Folder 86: 8)
      - "Ko vtoroi godovshchine Korpusa Mira,", 1963 (Folder 86: 9)
      - "Obratili li vy vnimanie?", 1963 (Folder 86: 10)
      - "Vstrechi so Stalinym, otzyvy o Staline,", 1963 (Folder 86: 11)
      - "Molodezhnaia," #55-57, 1964 (Folder 86: 12-13)
      - "K konchine Prem'era Izrailia L. Eshkolia,", 1969 (Folder 86: 14)
      - "O 14-om Mezhdunarodnom Filosofskom Kongresse,", 1968 (Folder 86: 15)
      - "Ob odnoi polemike filosofov,", 1968 (Folder 86: 16)
      - "K publikatsii knigi L. Vladimirova "Rossiia bez prikras i umolchanii,", 1969 (Folder 86: 17)
      - "Kto est' kto: Premier Ministr Izrailia Golda Meir,", 1969 (Folder 86: 18)
      - "Sovremennyi vostochno-evropeiskii revizionizm," #1-23, 1969 (Box-folder 87: 1-3)
      - "Vstrechi so slushateliami,", 1971 1973 1974 (Folder 87: 4)
      - "O sbornike stikhov S. Golovanova Urema,", 1972 (Folder 87: 5)
      - "Nauka i obshchestvo," #1-87, 1974-1976 (Folder 87: 6-9)
      - "Nauka i obshchestvo," #1-87, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 88: 1-4)
      - "Sotsiologiia nauki," #1-119, 1975-1977 (Folder 88: 5-6)
      - "Sotsiologiia nauki," #1-119, 1975-1977 (Box 89-90)
      - "Svidetel'stva,", 1976 (Box 91)
        - "Rasskaz V. Shalamova Nachal'nik politotdela," #31 (Folder 91: 1)
        - "Rasskaz V. Shalamova Kak eto nachalos'," #32-33 (Folder 91: 2)
        - "Otkrytoe pis'mo poeta E. Yevtushenko o politike sokrytiia i izvrashcheniia istoricheskoi pravdy," #34 (Folder 91: 3)
        - "Svidetel'stva iz lagernogo fol'klora," #35-36 (Folder 91: 4)
        - "Svidetel'stvo V. Shalamova v rasskaze "Sherri-Brendi"; "Poety-pobochnye deti Rossii"; "Pesni," #37 (Folder 91: 5)
        - "Soobshchil li pravdu sekretar' gorkoma KPSS Vorkuty Chernov?" (Folder 91: 6)
      - "60 Let kontrolia nad naukoi,", 1977
        - "Verny li utverzhdeniia rukovoditelei KPSS o tom, chto sovetskaia nauka zaniala 'peredovye rubezhi' mirovogo razvitiia znanii?" #2 (Folder 91: 7)
        - "Pochemu utverzhdeniia o tom, chto teoriia otnositel'nosti protivorechit nauchnomu mirovozzreniiu, stali v SSSR s nachala 20-kh godov ofitsial'noi ustanovkoi?" #3 (Folder 91: 8)
        - "O prichinakh, pobudivshikh ideologicheskikh kontrolerov sovetskoi nauki obiavit' v nachale 20-kh godov teoriiu otnositel'nosti burzhuaznoi, idealisticheskoi, neistinnoi," #4 (Folder 91: 9)
      - "K sorokaletiiu ezhovshchiny,", 1977 (Folder 91: 10)
      - Miscellaneous (Folder 91: 11-12)
    - Zemtsov, Ilia, 1974
      - General (Folder 91: 13)
      - Broadcast transcripts (Folder 91: 14)
    - Zinoviev, Aleksandr.
      - General (Folder 91: 15)
      - Broadcast transcripts (Folder 91: 15)
      - Broadcast transcripts (Box-folder 92: 1-5)
- SOVIET LABOR CAMPS FILE, 1955-1980 (Box 93)
  See also INCREMENTAL MATERIALS
  - Anecdotes (Folder 93: 1-8)
  - Anecdotes (Box 94-96)
  - Anecdotes (Box-folder 97: 1-4)
  - Poetry (Folder 97: 5-7)
  - Poetry (Box-folder 98: 1-5)
  - Slang dictionaries and sayings (Folder 98: 6-8)
  - Slang dictionaries and sayings (Box-folder 99: 1-5)
  - Songs.
    See also CORRESPONDENCE/Patch, I.
    - General
      - General (Folder 99: 6-7)
      - General (Box 100-101)
      - General (Box-folder 102: 1)
      - Lists of camp songs (Folder 102: 2)
      - Memoranda regarding recording of camp songs (Folder 102: 3)
      - Reviews
        - Radio Liberty (Folder 102: 4)
        - Soviet media (Folder 102: 5)
    - About
      - Dissidents (Folder 102: 6-8)
      - Dissidents (Box-folder 103: 1-5)
      - Politics (Folder 103: 6)
    - Performed by
      - Okudzhava, Bulat (Folder 103: 7)
      - Pylaev (Folder 103: 8)
      - Women (Folder 104: 1)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 104: 2)
- WRITINGS BY OTHERS, 1958-1987
  - Unidentified (Folder 104: 3-5)
  - Amalrik, Andrei, "Prosushchestvuet li Sovetskii Soiuz do 1984 goda?", 1969 (Folder 104: 6)
  - Dykhovichnyi, V. and M. Slobodskoi, V. Mass, M. Chervinskii, "Gurii L'vovich Sinichkin,", 1964 (Folder 104: 7)
  - Erenburg, I., 1963-1967 (Folder 104: 8)
  - Fedoseev, Anatolii, 1971-1979 (Folder 104: 9)
  - Kaplan, K., "Mysli o politicheskikh protsessakh,", 1968 (Folder 104: 10)
  - Kaplan, K., "Mysli o politicheskikh protsessakh,", 1968 (Box-folder 105: 1)
  - Ktorova, Alla, 1961-1964 (Folder 105: 2)
  - Luxemburg, Rosa, 1968 (Folder 105: 3)
  - Marchenko, Anatolii, Moi pokazaniia, 1967 (Folder 105: 4-5)
  - Miller, D., 1964 (Folder 105: 6)
  - Navrozov, Lev, 1987-1990 (Folder 105: 7)
  - Panin, Dmitrii, "O prirode ekspluatatsii,", 1973 (Box-folder 106: 1)
  - Philby, Kim, 1985-1989 (Folder 106: 2)
  - Popovskii, Mark, "Obmanutaia nauka,", 1976 (Folder 106: 3)
  - Removskii, Shiman, "Koliuchie tropy" (Folder 106: 4)
  - Shalamov, Varllam (Box-folder 107: 1-2)
  - Solzhenitsyn, Aleksandr.
    See also RADIO LIBERTY BROADCAST TRANSCRIPTS/Solzhenitsyn, Aleksandr
    - Appeal, 1974 (Folder 107: 3)
    - Articles (Folder 107: 4)
    - Interviews (Folder 107: 5-6)
    - Nobel lecture (Folder 107: 7)
    - Press conferences (Box-folder 108: 1)
    - Speeches (Folder 108: 2)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 108: 3-5)
  - Tetenov, Nikolai, 1977-1987 (Box-folder 109: 1)
  - Troepolskii, Gavriil, "V kamyshakh," Novyi Mir,, #4, 1963 (Folder 109: 2)
  - Zemtsov, Ilia
    - General (Folder 109: 3)
    - Articles, 1974-1978 (Folder 109: 4-7)
    - Articles, 1974-1978 (Box-folder 110: 1)
  - Zinoviev, Aleksandr
    - Articles (Folder 110: 2-4)
    - Lecture (Folder 110: 5)
  - Miscellaneous. (Folder 110: 6-7)
    Includes short stories
  - Miscellaneous. (Box-folder 111: 1-6)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box-folder 112: 1-3)
- PRINTED MATTER, 1958-1976
  Articles and brochures, relating to various activities of Radio Liberty, arranged chronologically
  - 1958-1959 (Folder 112: 4)
  - 1960-1961 (Folder 112: 5)
  - 1961 (Folder 112: 6)
  - 1962-1965 (Box-folder 113: 1)
  - 1967 (Folder 113: 2)
  - 1967-1968 (Folder 113: 3)
  - 1969 (Folder 113: 4)
  - 1971 (Box-folder 114: 1)
  - 1974-1975 (Folder 114: 2)
  - 1976 (Folder 114: 3)
- PHOTOGRAPHS, n.d.
  - 7 prints depicting Alexander and Nomi Vardy on different occasions with Ronalds, American Chief of the Russian desk, Radio Liberty; Peronansky, Chief of the Russian desk; Lev Predelechevsky, Military commentator, Russian desk (Folder 114: 4)
  - 13 prints depicting Radio Liberty representatives Joe Scott, Walter Scott, Ronalds, Lodesseen, Van der Rhoer, Robert Tuck, Victor Rossinski, Perry, Victor Gregory, Vitalii Zakuta, Kromiadi, Emil Krotkii, Malyshev, Iosefogly, Peronansky, Evgenii Garanin, Keith Bush, Leonid Pylaev, Georgii and Ekaterina Ostroverkhov, Victoria Mondich (Folder 114: 5)
  - 1 print depicting Tagiberli Devlet, Omarkhan Akhmetdzhan, Keigu Asan (Folder 114: 6)
  - 5 prints of illustrations for Vardy's books (Folder 114: 7)
  - 8 unidentified prints (Folder 114: 8)
  - 4 prints depicting Alexander and Nomi Vardy and others upon the 10th anniversary of Nomi Vardy's work at Radio Liberty; and 1 print depicting Soviet philosophers at the 14th International Philosophy Congress in Vienna, Austria (Photo-file Envelope A)
- AUDIOTAPES, 1963-1980
  167 phonotapes and phonotape cassettes
  - Broadcasts (Box 115-119)
  - Interviews (Box 120)
  - Songs (Box 120-126)
- OVERSIZE MATERIAL, 1955-1989 (Box 127)
  Scrapbook of clippings collected by Vardy, relating to him
- INCREMENTAL MATERIALS, 1940-2002 (Box 128)
  - Biographical file, 1940-1989
    - List of publications, n.d. (Folder 128: 1)
    - Personal correspondence, n.d., 1940-1983 (Folder 128: 2)
    - Presidential Certificate of Appreciation (George Bush), 1989 August (Folder 128: 3)
  - Correspondence, 1962-1988
    - Begin, Menachem, 1988 (Folder 128: 4)
    - Belinkov, Arkadiy, 1970 (Folder 128: 5)
    - Hurwitz, Z. H., 1988 (Folder 128: 6)
    - Perreault, Linda (Director of Correspondence for First Lady Nancy Reagan), 1987 (Folder 128: 7)
    - Salmini, Ambrose, 1962 (Folder 128: 8)
    - Sztein, E., 1970 (Folder 128: 9)
    - Zakuta, Viktor, 1964 (Folder 128: 10)
    - Miscellany, 1985-1989 (Folder 128: 11)
  - Speeches and writings, 1962-1989
    - General
      - Untitled holographs, n.d. (Folder 128: 12)
      - "Dialekticheskii materialism i sovremennoe nauchnoe miroponimanie,", n.d. (Folder 128: 13)
        See also SPEECHES AND WRITINGS.
        Typescript
      - "Drevnie kamni Evropy,", n.d. (Folder 128: 14)
        Holograph
      - "Izyskateli,", n.d. (Folder 128: 15)
      - "Kommunistische Philosophie: Analyse und Alternativen," (Folder 128: 16)
      - "Kto vinovat?", n.d. (Folder 128: 17)
      - "Mozhno li vygorodit' Solzhenitsyna,", n.d. (Folder 129: 1)
      - "Nogi raznye,", n.d. (Folder 129: 2)
      - "O roli sub'ektivnogo faktora, psikhicheskogo zdorov'ia naselenia i ionosfery v obshchestvennom razvitii,", n.d. (Folder 129: 3)
      - "Potomok konkvistadorov,", n.d. (Folder 129: 4)
      - "Tozhe sverkhchelovek,", n.d. (Folder 129: 5)
      - "Tsena neitraliteta,", n.d. (Folder 129: 6)
      - "Who in the USSR Needs Dictatorship and Its Expansionism?" (Folder 129: 7)
      - "Kritika dialektiki marksizma-leninizma," Posev, 1962 December. (Folder 129: 8)
        Printed copy
      - "Conflicts in Marxism-Leninism Materialist Ontology," Bulletin: Institute for the Study of the USSR, 1963. (Folder 129: 9)
      - "K kritike marksistsko-leninskoi dialektiki," Uchenye zapiski instituta po izucheniu SSSR, 1963. (Folder 129: 10)
        Printed copy in Russian and typescript in English
      - Das Eisloch (Prorub), 1964. (Folder 129: 11)
      - "Oppozitsia vnutri sovetskogo filosofskogo fronta," Posev, 1964 November. (Folder 129: 12)
      - "Kritika printsipov marksistsko-leninskoi dialektiki," Posev, 1965 January. (Folder 129: 13)
      - "Tupik marksistskoi dialektiki," Posev, 1965 February. (Folder 129: 14)
      - "Parapsychology Versus Marxism-Leninism," Studies of the Soviet Union (Bulletin: Institute for the Study of the USSR), 1966. (Folder 129: 15)
      - Review on A. Gouriévitch, Lois générales et nécessité concrète en histoire, (Voprosy istorii, Moscow, 1965), Problèmes soviétiques, 1966. (Folder 129: 16)
      - "The Soviet Leaders and the Chinese Dilemma," Bulletin: Institute for the Study of the USSR, Published under pseudonym Alexander Kashin., 1966. (Folder 129: 17)
      - "Zhizn' i diamat," Posev, 1966 April. (Folder 129: 18)
      - "Istoria nichem ne zaprogrammirovana," Posev, 1966 May. (Folder 129: 19)
      - "O 'nauchnom kommunisme'," Posev, 1966 July. (Folder 129: 20)
      - "Dialektika i sovremennoe estestvoznanie," Soobshchenia instituta po izucheniu SSSR, 1967. (Folder 129: 21)
      - "Simposium po 'Dialektike sovremennogo estestvoznania'," Soobshchenia instituta po izucheniu SSSR, 1967. (Folder 130: 1)
        Includes French version "Le symposium international sur 'la dialectique et les sciences naturelles modernes'," Problèmes soviétiques (Institut d'études sur l'URSS), 1967. Printed copy
      - "Sovetskie uchenye o nesostoiatel'nosti marksistsko-leninskoi dialektiki," Posev, 1967 April. (Folder 130: 2)
      - "Eshche ob akademike V. Foke...," Posev, 1967 June. (Folder 130: 3)
      - "'Poedinok' parapsikhologii s marksizmom," Posev, 1967 July. (Folder 130: 4)
      - "Raskol novogo klassa, russkaia nauka I tekhnologia protiv kommunisma," Posev, 1967 October. (Folder 130: 5)
      - "Raskol novogo klassa," Posev, Review of Albert Parry, The New Class Divided; Science and Technology Versus Communism, 1966., 1967 October. (Folder 130: 6)